<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roots on Monasca</title>
    <link>http://monasca.io/root/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Roots on Monasca</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2015 Hewlett Packard Enterprise</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 18:32:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://monasca.io/root/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://monasca.io/root/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 18:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://monasca.io/root/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Monasca provides an open-source multi-tenant, highly scalable, performant, fault-tolerant monitoring-as-a-service solution.
Metrics can be published to the Monasca API, stored and queried.
Alarms can be created and notifications, such as email, can be sent when alarms transition state.
Support for complex event processing and logging is in progress.
Monasca builds an extensible platform for advanced monitoring services that can be used by both operators and tenants to gain operational insight and visibilty, ensuring availabilty and stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;who-is-involved:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Who is involved?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The members of the Monasca team are primarily composed of companies, organizations and individuals involved in development and deployment of OpenStack.
Monasca is in the process of applying for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openstack.org/&#34;&gt;OpenStack&lt;/a&gt; governance.
Currently, Monasca is hosted in Github under the Stackforge organization, and will move to the OpenStack organization when approved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the major companies involved with developing and/or deploying Monasca include the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hewlett-Packard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time Warner Cable (TWC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fujitsu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cisco&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rackspace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;technologies:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Technologies&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monasca is written in both Java and Python. Several of the components in Monasca started out in Java. However, the go-forward language for Monasca is Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monasca is built on several open-source technologies including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stacktach.com/&#34;&gt;StackTach.v3&lt;/a&gt; Real-time event stream processing system. StackTach.v3 is used in the Monasca Event processing system that is under development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kafka.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache Kafka&lt;/a&gt; A high-throughput distributed messaging system. Kafka is a central component in Monasca and provides the infranstructure for all internal communications between components.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://storm.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache Storm&lt;/a&gt; Apache Storm is a free and open source distributed realtime computation system. Apache Storm is used in the Monasca Threshold Engine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zookeeper.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache ZooKeeper&lt;/a&gt; Apache ZooKeeper is is by Kafka and Storm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://influxdb.com/&#34;&gt;InfluxDB&lt;/a&gt; An open-source distributed time series database with no external dependencies. InfluxDB is one of the supported databases for storing metrics and alarm history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mysql.com/&#34;&gt;MySQL&lt;/a&gt; MySQL is a freely available open source Relational Database Management System (RDBMS) that uses Structured Query Language (SQL). SQL is the most popular language for adding, accessing and managing content in a database. It is most noted for its quick processing, proven reliability, ease and flexibility of use. MySQL is one of the supported databases for the Monasca Config Database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grafana.org&#34;&gt;Grafana&lt;/a&gt; is an open source, feature rich metrics dashboard and graph editor. Support for Monasca as a data source in Grafana has been added.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, Monasca optionally supports the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vertica.com/&#34;&gt;HP Vertica&lt;/a&gt; HP Vertica delivers the most advanced SQL analytics as a standards-based relational database with full support for SQL, JDBC, and ODBC. Vertica is one of the supported databases for storing metrics and alarm history within Monasca.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;licensing:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Licensing&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All code has been developed under an Apache 2.0 license and has no restrictions on distribution or deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;acknowledgments:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monasca uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yourkit.com/&#34;&gt;YourKit Java Profiler&lt;/a&gt; for Java development and performance analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yourkit.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.yourkit.com/images/yklogo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34; title=&#34;YourKit&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>architecture</title>
      <link>http://monasca.io/root/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 18:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://monasca.io/root/architecture/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Monasca is a highly performant, scalable, fault-tolerant and extensible micro-services messages bus based architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It uses a REST API for high-speed metrics processing and querying and has a streaming alarm engine and notification engine. All of these are linked
using the messaging system &lt;a href=&#34;https://kafka.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Kafka&lt;/a&gt;. Every component in the system is built with High Availability in mind and can grow
horizontally to allow for monitoring of very large systems.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://monasca.io/img/Monasca-arch-component-diagram.png&#34; alt=&#34;Monasca Architecture&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;metrics-alarm-flow:1bf455b3a3c6e1e40be41ef6023b75eb&#34;&gt;Metrics/Alarm Flow&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/components/api/&#34;&gt;Monasca API&lt;/a&gt; is the gateway for all interaction with Monasca. In a typical scenario &lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/components/metrics&#34;&gt;metrics&lt;/a&gt;
are collected by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/components/agent/&#34;&gt;Monasca Agent&lt;/a&gt; running on a system and sent to the Monasca API. The api then puts the metrics onto the Kafak queue.
From here the &lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/components/persister/&#34;&gt;Monasca Persister&lt;/a&gt; consumes metrics and writes them to our &lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/components/metrics_db/&#34;&gt;Metrics database&lt;/a&gt;. The
&lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/components/alarms/&#34;&gt;Monasca Threshold Engine&lt;/a&gt; also consumes the metrics and uses them to evaluate &lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/components/alarms/&#34;&gt;alarms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point the metrics are in our system and can be be retrieved from the Monasca API, either directly or through one of our other components
such as the Horizon plugin or the &lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/components/cli&#34;&gt;Monasca CLI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the threshold engine evaluates the metrics against the alarms it can create alarm state transition events. These are published back onto Kafka
and are read by both the persister and &lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/components/notifications/&#34;&gt;Notification Engine&lt;/a&gt;. The persister simply writes the alarm transitions to the
DB for future retrieval. The notification engine will send a notification of the configured type for appropriate state transitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the components discussed above we also have a configuration database used for storing information such as alarm definitions and
notification methods. This db can be either mysql or postgresql.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future Components&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The events and transform engines are actively being worked on and will soon be incorporated. In addition some proof of concept work has been done
for an Anomaly detection engine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dev</title>
      <link>http://monasca.io/root/dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 17:04:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://monasca.io/root/dev/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Monasca is an active project seeking to be a part of the OpenStack community and welcomes new development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;openstack-community:9ebf8dc1d918e9d82885a54b6ce06af5&#34;&gt;OpenStack Community&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have &lt;a href=&#34;https://review.openstack.org/#/c/213183/&#34;&gt;submitted&lt;/a&gt; to be included into OpenStack and follow OpenStack
&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/How_To_Contribute&#34;&gt;contribution guidelines&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.openstack.org/developer/hacking/&#34;&gt;code standards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our project has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://launchpad.net/monasca&#34;&gt;launchpad site&lt;/a&gt; which is used for bug tracking. The project mailing list is also hosted on launchpad,
see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://launchpad.net/~monasca&#34;&gt;team page&lt;/a&gt; for details on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details on the team meetings are found on this &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Meetings/Monasca&#34;&gt;OpenStack wiki page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;code-contributions:9ebf8dc1d918e9d82885a54b6ce06af5&#34;&gt;Code Contributions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we await our full inclusion into OpenStack our code is hosted as part of stackforge and can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stackforge?query=monasca&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/dev/vagrant/&#34;&gt;Monasca Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; environment is the primary setup used for development of Monasca. More information on testing Monasca can be found
at our &lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/dev/testing/&#34;&gt;testing page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>deployment</title>
      <link>http://monasca.io/root/deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 17:09:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://monasca.io/root/deployment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Monasca is a system built for large scale deployments. One side effect of this is there are many components in the system each of which is an
installation in and of itself. The end result of this is that I highly recommend you use a configuration management system to install Monasca.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HP Monasca team has published a set of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ansible.com/home&#34;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt; roles that can be used to install and configure Monasca on
Debian/Ubuntu based machines. These roles all are in repos that start with &amp;lsquo;ansible-&amp;rsquo; and are available on github under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hpcloud-mon?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;query=ansible-&#34;&gt;hpcloud-mon organization&lt;/a&gt;. These roles are used in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/dev/vagrant/&#34;&gt;Monasca Vagrant&lt;/a&gt;
development environment but are also used internally at HP for full HA installations of Monasca.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Ansible roles a &lt;a href=&#34;https://puppetlabs.com/&#34;&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt; module is maintained by the Monasca community in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openstack/puppet-monasca&#34;&gt;puppet-monasca&lt;/a&gt; git repository.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>coming soon</title>
      <link>http://monasca.io/root/coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 18:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://monasca.io/root/coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Monasca will be adding support for the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging: In the style of Loggly, support for an authenticated multi-tenant logging solution is in progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complex Event Processing:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cassandra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ceilosca, integration with Ceilometer and Monasca.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>demo</title>
      <link>http://monasca.io/root/demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 10:17:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://monasca.io/root/demo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The primary demo for environment for Monasca is a Docker Image.  To avoid setting all of Monasca up just to investigate it I have created
a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/r/monasca/demo/&#34;&gt;demo image&lt;/a&gt; that contains all of the Monasca components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This image can be run via &lt;a href=&#34;https://kitematic.com/&#34;&gt;kitematic&lt;/a&gt; or directly in a Docker installation. If running with Docker simply run&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker run -d -p 80:80 -p 8080:8080 -p 5000:5000 --name monasca monasca/demo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the image will download and start. The demo has a keystone user &lt;code&gt;mini-mon&lt;/code&gt; with the password &lt;code&gt;password&lt;/code&gt;. The Monasca horizon plugin is available
on port 80, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/components/api/&#34;&gt;Monasca API&lt;/a&gt; on port 8080 and the embedded keystone on port 5000. Additionally if you shell into the environment
a set of env variables is available at &lt;code&gt;/setup/env.sh&lt;/code&gt; so you can simple source this file and begin using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/components/cli&#34;&gt;Monasca CLI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;alternatives:33d3cedc2d74629a40b36bf8cf252b87&#34;&gt;Alternatives&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the Docker demo the Monasca uses a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; environment for development and this can be used as an alternative
demo environment. It is a bit more involved to setup but works well, more information at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://monasca.io/dev/vagrant/&#34;&gt;development with vagrant page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>